Guide to the Dorothy Porter Wesley Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Series II. Professional Papers, 1869-2003
  - General, 1869-2010
    - Afro-American Historical and Genealogical Society, 1991 Annual Conference (Box 122, Folder 995)
    - The Afro-American Institute for Historical Preservation and Community Development, 1994- (Box 123, Folder 996)
    - Afro-American Resources and Library Manpower (AARLM), 1972- (Box 123, Folder 997)
    - Alpha Phi Alpha Fraternity, 1995- (Box 123, Folder 998)
    - Alumni Directory, School of Library of Information Service, Columbia University, 1980- (Box 123, Folder 999)
    - American Antiquarian Society, 1973- (Box 123, Folder 1000)
    - American Association of University Women Yearbook, 1950-1952 (Box 123, Folder 1001)
    - American Historical Association, 1978- (Box 123, Folder 1002)
    - American Library Association, 1972- (Box 123, Folder 1003)
    - American Negro Biographical Association, 1934- (Box 123, Folder 1004)
    - An Evening of Poets, 1949- (Box 123, Folder 1005)
    - Annual Observance of National Book Week, 1953- (Box 123, Folder 1006)
    - Assembly of Librarians of the Americas, 1947- (Box 123, Folder 1007)
    - Association of Black Women Historians, 1989- (Box 123, Folder 1008)
    - Association of Caribbean University and Research Libraries, 1970-1974 (Box 123, Folder 1009)
    - The Association for the Study of African American Life and History, 1937-1984 (Box 124, Folder 1010-1016)
    - The Association for the Study of African American Life and History, 1984-1990 (Box 125, Folder 1017-1022)
    - The Association for the Study of African American Life and History, 1990-1992 (Box 126, Folder 1023-1027)
    - The Association for the Study of African American Life and History, 1992- (Box 127, Folder 1028-1030)
    - The Association for the Study of African American Life and History, 1993- (Box 128, Folder 1031-1036)
    - The Association for the Study of African American Life and History, 1993-2010 (Box 129, Folder 1037-1042)
    - Beacon Advisory Board on Black History, 1969- (Box 130, Folder 1043)
    - Bethune Museum and Archives for Black Women's History, 1989-1990 (Box 130, Folder 1044)
    - Bibliography aids, Undated (Box 130, Folder 1045)
    - Bibliography Society of America, 1945- (Box 130, Folder 1046)
    - Black Abolitionists Papers Project, 1978-1980 (Box 130, Folder 1047-1048)
    - Black Academy of Arts and Letters Inc., 1970-1972 (Box 130, Folder 1049-1052)
    - Black Academy of Arts and Letters Inc., 1972-1973 (Box 131, Folder 1053)
    - Black Bibliophiles and Collectors: A National Symposium, 1981-1993 (Box 131, Folder 1054-1059)
    - Black Bibliophiles and Collectors: A National Symposium, 1981-1993 (Box 132, Folder 1060)
    - Black Bibliophiles and Collectors: A National Symposium, 1968-1993 (Box 178 (Oversize), Folder 1581)
    - Black Biographical Dictionaries 1790-1950, 1990-1991 (Box 132, Folder 1061)
    - Black History Month Observance, 2003- (Box 132, Folder 1062)
    - Black Studies Seminar, 1968-1970 (Box 132, Folder 1063-1064)
    - Black Women in Sisterhood for Action, 1990- (Box 132, Folder 1065)
    - Blassingame Paper, 1968- (Box 132, Folder 1066)
    - Bobbs-Merrill Reprints, Undated (Box 132, Folder 1067)
    - Book Orders, 1986-1987 (Box 133, Folder 1068)
    - Brazil, 1959-1992 (Box 133, Folder 1069-1071)
    - Brazil, 1974- (Box 178 (Oversize), Folder 1582)
    - Brazil card notes, box 1, Undated (Box 182 (Oversize))
    - Brazil card notes, box 1. Catalog card box (restricted fragile), Undated (Box 183)
      Conditions Governing Access
      Catalog card box
    - Brazil card notes, box 2, Undated (Box 184)
    - Butcher-Built Doll House, appraisal, 1948-1995 (Box 133, Folder 1072)
    - Carlson Publishing Inc., 1991-1993 (Box 133, Folder 1073-1074)
    - Catalogue of Lovedale Press Publications, 1970- (Box 133, Folder 1075)
    - Charles Eaton Burch Memorial Lecture, introductory notes and press release, 1972-1973 (Box 133, Folder 1076)
    - The Charles H. Thomas Memorial Lecture memorandum, 1988-1995 (Box 133, Folder 1077)
    - The Collegiate Publishing Company, 1962-1979 (Box 133, Folder 1078)
    - The Collington Letter, 1985- (Box 133, Folder 1079)
    - Colored Author Collection, 1969-1971 (Box 133, Folder 1080)
    - Columbia University, School of Library Service (Course Work), 1926-1936 (Box 134, Folder 1081-1088)
    - Columbia University, School of Library Service (Course Work), 1926-1936 (Box 135, Folder 1089-1093)
    - Commision study of the Negro National Museum and Library (notes), 1968- (Box 135, Folder 1094)
    - Committee on Civil Disorders (correspondence and notes), 1967- (Box 135, Folder 1095)
    - Committee on Culture and International Change report, 1965- (Box 135, Folder 1096)
    - Committee on the Department of Afro-American Studies at Howard University, 1974-1975 (Box 135, Folder 1097)
    - Conference on Manding Studies, 1972- (Box 136, Folder 1098)
    - Conference of Negro Writers and Artists, 1958- (Box 136, Folder 1099)
    - The Contribution of the Negro to the Spanish American and Brazilian Poetry and Fiction: A Bibliographical Essay. (project proposal), Undated (Box 136, Folder 1100)
    - Coretta Scott King Award and Exhibit, 1972- (Box 136, Folder 1101)
    - Crisis Advisory Committee, 1975- (Box 136, Folder 1102)
    - Cuba, notes and photographs, 1940-1945 (Box 136, Folder 1103)
    - Cuba, notes and photographs, 1940- (Box 178 (Oversize), Folder 1583)
    - Curricululum Vitae (cv), 1944-1994 (Box 136, Folder 1104-1110)
    - Curricululum Vitae (cv), 1944-1994 (Box 137, Folder 1111-1113)
    - D.C. Commission on the Arts and Humanities, 1973- (Box 137, Folder 1114)
    - D.C. Historical Records Board, 1978-1983 (Box 137, Folder 1115)
    - Dakar, Senegal Conference, 1971- (Box 137, Folder 1116)
    - Dedication of the Howard University Museum, 1979- (Box 137, Folder 1117)
    - Delta Sigma Theta Sorority, 1941-1986 (Box 137, Folder 1118-1119)
    - Department of Health, Education, and Welfare Public Health Service, 1976- (Box 137, Folder 1120)
    - The Dialectic of Double-Consciousness in Black Freedom Celebrations, 1973- (Box 138, Folder 1121)
    - Dictionary of American Negro Biography, 1971-1978 (Box 138, Folder 1122-1126)
    - Dorothy Porter Wesley Files at Howard University, Circa 1968-1971 (Box 138, Folder 1127)
    - Dorothy Porter Wesley Research Center, Inc, 1991-2001 (Box 138, Folder 1128-1130)
    - Dorothy Porter Wesley Research Center, Inc, 1991-2001 (Box 139, Folder 1131-1133)
    - Duke University Conference on International Studies, 1966- (Box 139, Folder 1134)
    - Eliza S. Hoffman Music Festival Project, 1975- (Box 139, Folder 1135)
    - Elvin Montgomery Booklets, 1992- (Box 139, Folder 1136)
    - Executive Council Meeting minutes, 1971- (Box 139, Folder 1137)
    - Exhibition notes on black poetry, Circa 1986 (Box 139, Folder 1138)
    - Federal Writers Project, 1936-2001 (Box 139, Folder 1139)
    - Final Report on the Workshop on Bibliographic and Other Resources for a Study of the American Negro, 1968- (Box 139, Folder 1140)
    - Fisk University, 1968-1980 (Box 139, Folder 1141)
    - Fisk University, 1968-1980 (Box 140, Folder 1142-1144)
    - Ford Foundation, 1954-1977 (Box 140, Folder 1145-1151)
    - Ford Foundation, 1964- (Box 178 (Oversize), Folder 1584)
    - Frederick Douglas Papers, 1987- (Box 140, Folder 1152)
    - G.K. Hall Reference Books, 1981- (Box 140, Folder 1153)
    - Harvard University, W.E.B. Dubois Institute, 1988-1995 (Box 141, Folder 1154-1158)
    - Harvard University, W.E.B. Dubois Institute, 1988-1994 (Box 178 (Oversize), Folder 1585)
    - Heritage Gallery Recent Acquisitions, 1987- (Box 141, Folder 1159)
    - Historical Records Advisory Board, 1982-1983 (Box 141, Folder 1160)
    - Historical Research Notes, 1941-1942 (Box 141, Folder 1161)
    - The Historical Society of Washington D.C., 1989 Annual Report (Box 141, Folder 1162)
    - Howard University, Archives Committee, 1941-1965 (Box 141, Folder 1163)
    - Howard University, Charter Day Convocation, 1938-1994 (Box 141, Folder 1164)
    - Howard University, College of Fine Arts, Circa 1990 (Box 142, Folder 1165)
    - Howard University, Faculty Wives Club, 1947-1979 (Box 142, Folder 1166)
    - Howard University, Founders Library Booklist, 1939- (Box 142, Folder 1167)
    - Howard University Library, Circa 1977 (Box 142, Folder 1168)
    - Howard University Museum Dedication, 1969-1979 (Box 142, Folder 1169)
    - Howard University, National Negro Library and Museum, 1938- (Box 142, Folder 1170)
    - Howard University Press, Circa 1990 (Box 142, Folder 1171)
    - Howard University Underground Railroad Workshop, 1992- (Box 142, Folder 1172)
    - Howard University Women's Club, 1987- (Box 142, Folder 1173)
    - Ibadan Conference, 1962- (Box 142, Folder 1174)
    - International Conference on African Bibliography, 1967- (Box 142, Folder 1175)
    - International Congress of Africanists, 1962- (Box 142, Folder 1176)
    - International Relations Club of Greater Washington, 1957-1963 (Box 142, Folder 1177)
    - Interview of Dorothy Porter Wesley by James Nazir Conyers, 1993- (Box 142, Folder 1178)
    - Interview of Dorothy Porter Wesley by James Hatch and Camille Billops, 1990- (Box 142, Folder 1179)
    - Invisible Howard Graduates, Administrators, Heads of Departments Professors, and Librarians, Undated (Box 142, Folder 1180)
    - Jack and Jill of America Inc., 1956- (Box 142, Folder 1181)
    - Jesse Edward Moorland, letters and notes on Plantation Songs, 1909-1915 (Box 142, Folder 1182)
    - John Cromwell Collection, 1974- (Box 143, Folder 1183)
    - Journal of Negro Education Index, 1932-1979 (Box 143, Folder 1184)
    - The Julia Davis Collection, 1971- (Box 143, Folder 1185)
    - King Memorial Center, 1968- (Box 143, Folder 1186)
    - A Legacy Unfolded by Gerald L. Durley (draft), 1979- (Box 143, Folder 1187-1190)
    - Library of Congress, 1973-1976 (Box 144, Folder 1191)
    - Library of Congress, 1973- (Box 178 (Oversize), Folder 1586)
    - Library of Congress, catalog cards on the Negro in the United States, Brazil and Africa, Undated (Box 180)
    - Library of Congress, catalog cards on the Negro in the United States, Brazil and Africa. Catalog card box, Undated (Box 181)
    - Lincoln University, 1987- (Box 144, Folder 1192)
    - Luso-Brazillian Conference, 1950-1959 (Box 144, Folder 1193)
    - Metropolitan A.M.E. Church, 1990- (Box 144, Folder 1194)
    - Mid-Atlantic Regional Archives Conference, 1972-1979 (Box 144, Folder 1195)
    - Miner Hall materials, 1936- (Box 144, Folder 1196)
    - Moorland Spingarn Research Center, building the collection (contains correspondence), 1929-1973 (Box 144, Folder 1197-1199)
    - Moorland Spingarn Research Center, Finding Aids, 1981-1984 (Box 144, Folder 1200-1203)
    - Moorland Spingarn Research Center, Finding Aids, 1981-1984 (Box 145, Folder 1204-1205)
    - Moorland Spingarn Research Center informational brochures and notes, 1958-1983 (Box 145, Folder 1206)
    - Moorland Spingarn Research Center, Items, 1972- (Box 145, Folder 1207)
    - Moorland Spingarn Research Center, Lecture Notes, 1940- (Box 145, Folder 1208)
    - Moorland Spingarn Research Center, Memorandum, 1972-1974 (Box 145, Folder 1209)
    - Moorland Spingarn Research Center, Reports and brochures, 1869-1978 (Box 145, Folder 1210)
    - Moorland Spingarn Research Center, Staff, Circa 1970 (Box 145, Folder 1211)
    - Morgan State University, 1976- (Box 145, Folder 1212)
    - Mordecai Wyatt Johnson, A Bibliography of his Years at Howard University compiled by James P. Johnson, Janet L. Sims and Gail A. Kostinko, 1976- (Box 145, Folder 1213)
    - National Archives and Records Administration, 1984- (Box 146, Folder 1214)
    - National Association of Colored Women's Clubs, Inc., 1992- (Box 146, Folder 1215-1216)
    - National Association for Equal Oppourtunity in Higher Education, 1994- (Box 146, Folder 1217)
    - National Black Museum Conference, 1980- (Box 146, Folder 1218)
    - National Council of Negro Women, 1940-1992 (Box 146, Folder 1219-1220)
    - National Education Association, 1967- (Box 146, Folder 1221)
    - National Endowment for the Humanties workshops, project proposals and reports, 1965-1994 (Box 146, Folder 1222-1225)
    - National Endowment for the Humanties workshops, project proposals and reports, 1965-1994 (Box 147, Folder 1226-1233)
    - National Endowment for the Humanties workshops, project proposals and reports, 1965-1994 (Box 148, Folder 1234-1238)
    - National Historical Publications Commission, 1974- (Box 148, Folder 1239)
    - National Survey of Historic Sites, 1973-1976 (Box 148, Folder 1240-1241)
    - Negro Spirituals by H.T. Burleigh, 1917- (Box 148, Folder 1242)
    - The Negro Writers Vision of America Conference, 1965-1979 (Box 148, Folder 1243)
    - Newspapers and Periodicals in Microform, 1967- (Box 148, Folder 1244)
    - Nigerian Library Association, 1962-1967 (Box 148, Folder 1245)
    - North American Negro Poets, 1934-1970 (Box 148, Folder 1246)
    - North Carolina Central University, Museum of Art, 1979- (Box 149, Folder 1247)
    - The Norton Anthology of Afro-American Literature, 1989- (Box 149, Folder 1248)
    - Omega Psi Phi Fraternity, Inc., The Oracle publication, 1938- (Box 149, Folder 1249)
    - Organization of American History Conference, 1979-1980 (Box 149, Folder 1250)
      - Oversize, 1979- (Box 178 (Oversize), Folder 1587)
    - Pan-African Union, Medina Centennial Celebration, 1952- (Box 149, Folder 1251)
    - Panoramas of Passage Conference, 1995- (Box 149, Folder 1252)
      - Oversize, Circa 1995 (Box 178 (Oversize), Folder 1588)
    - Patrick Hayes Concert event and seating, 1957- (Box 149, Folder 1253)
      - Oversize, Circa 1957 (Box 178 (Oversize), Folder 1589)
    - Phelps-Stokes Fund, 1973- (Box 149, Folder 1254)
    - The Philadelphia Afro-American Historical and Cultural Museum, 1983- (Box 149, Folder 1255)
    - Pictures in Dimension, Circa 1947-1958 (Box 149, Folder 1256)
    - "Poesia Negra" by James W. Ivy, Undated (Box 149, Folder 1257)
    - Prince Hall and Legacy by Charles H. Wesley, Book Signing Party, 1983- (Box 149, Folder 1258)
    - Radcliffe University, Black Women's Oral History Project, 1976-1986 (Box 149, Folder 1259-1260)
    - Radcliffe University, Black Women's Oral History Project, 1976-1986 (Box 150, Folder 1261-1265)
    - Radcliffe University, Black Women's Oral History Project, 1980-1985 (Box 178 (Oversize), Folder 1590)
    - Retirement Ceremony for Dorothy Porter Wesley, 1973- (Box 150, Folder 1266)
    - Retirement Ceremony for Dorothy Porter Wesley, 1973- (Box 178 (Oversize), Folder 1591)
    - Rosenwald Fund, 1944-1948 (Box 151, Folder 1267)
    - SALAM (Seminar in the Acquisition of Latin American Library Materials), 1968-1976 (Box 151, Folder 1268-1270)
    - Society of American Archivists, 1960-1974 (Box 151, Folder 1271-1272)
    - Southern Education Report, 1965-1968 (Box 152, Folder 1273-1274)
    - Supplement to Third Report Commission on Medical Education, 1929- (Box 152, Folder 1275)
    - Stylus membership, 1986- (Box 152, Folder 1276)
    - Toppin Committee, 1973- (Box 152, Folder 1277)
    - Tuskegee Institute, 1981- (Box 152, Folder 1278)
    - Two Abolitionists from Dixie, manuscript by David and Marian Grenberg, Undated (Box 152, Folder 1279-1281)
    - Union Catalog (notes), Circa 1970 (Box 152, Folder 1282)
    - United States Information Agency, 1962- (Box 152, Folder 1283)
      - Oversize, 1962- (Box 178 (Oversize), Folder 1592)
    - United States National Commision for UNESCO, 1965- (Box 152a, Folder 1284)
    - University of Pennsylvania, 1968- (Box 152a, Folder 1285)
    - Van Slycke and Reeside Travel Associates Itenerary, 1972- (Box 152a, Folder 1286)
    - Virgin Islands Trip (notes), 1970- (Box 152a, Folder 1287)
    - The W.E.B. Dubois Film Project, 1994- (Box 152a, Folder 1288)
    - Washington International Center, 1963- (Box 152a, Folder 1289)
    - Wesport Gallery, 1993- (Box 152a, Folder 1290-1291)
    - White House Library, 1980- (Box 152a, Folder 1292)
    - William Leo Hansberry, 1923-1955 (Box 152a, Folder 1293-1295)
    - Woodlawn Cemetary records (notes), Undated (Box 153, Folder 1296)
    - Work Progress Administration, National Union Catalog, 1939- (Box 153, Folder 1297-1299)
    - World Book Encylopedia (adverstisements), Circa 1951 (Box 153, Folder 1300)
    - Notes, Circa 1950-1995 (Box 153, Folder 1301-1306)
    - Notes, Circa 1950-1995 (Box 154, Folder 1307-1316)
    - Notes, Circa 1950-1995 (Box 155, Folder 1317-1321)
    - Clippings, Circa 1973-1991 (Box 155, Folder 1322)
      - Oversize, Circa 1973-1991 (Box 178 (Oversize), Folder 1593)
  - Speeches, 1942-1998
    - "Africana at Howard University", Undated (Box 156, Folder 1323)
    - "Alain Leroy Locke", Undated (Box 156, Folder 1324)
    - Altrusa Club of Washington, 1968-1969 (Box 156, Folder 1325)
    - The Annual Dorothy Porter Wesley Lecture, 1990-1998 (Box 156, Folder 1326-1334)
    - The Annual Dorothy Porter Wesley Lecture, Circa 1990-1998 (Box 178 (Oversize), Folder 1594)
    - The Annual Gladys G. Taylor Scholarship Awards Luncheon, 1992- (Box 157, Folder 1335)
    - The Annual Sojourner Truth Lecture, 1987-1988 (Box 157, Folder 1336)
    - "Benjamin Quarles", 1979- (Box 157, Folder 1337)
    - "Bibliographic and Other Aids to Historical Research", Undated (Box 157, Folder 1338)
    - "Bibliography and Library Resources", Undated (Box 157, Folder 1339)
    - "Bibliographic Resources to African and Afro-American Studies; With Special Reference to the Performing and Visual Arts", Undated (Box 157, Folder 1340)
    - "Black Women: Trail Blazers" speech at Women's Day St. Augustine Church, 1979- (Box 157, Folder 1341)
      - Oversize, 1979- (Box 178 (Oversize), Folder 1595)
    - "Blanche Wright" tribute, 1988- (Box 157, Folder 1342)
    - Caribbean Talk, 1969- (Box 157, Folder 1343)
    - Carter G.Woodson, reminisce, 1982-1993 (Box 157, Folder 1344)
    - Charlotte Forten dedication, 1990- (Box 157, Folder 1345)
    - "Collecting Afro-American Historical Materials", 1981- (Box 157, Folder 1346)
    - "Continuing Traditions: A Festival of Afro-American Arts", 1985- (Box 157, Folder 1347)
    - "Contributions of Negro Women", Undated (Box 157, Folder 1348)
    - Cornell-Africana Studies Talk, 1972- (Box 157, Folder 1349)
    - "Crispus Attucks", Undated (Box 157, Folder 1350)
    - DC Public Schools Sheppard Park speech and Drama Celebration, 1992-1993 (Box 157, Folder 1351)
    - Dedication of the S.E. Bailey Memorial Room, remarks, 1948- (Box 157, Folder 1352)
    - "Documentation on the Negro; Familiar and Less Familiar", 1968- (Box 157, Folder 1353)
    - Dorothy Porter Wesley on Collecting at the Third Zora Neale Hurston Festival of the Arts and Humanities, 1992- (Box 157, Folder 1354)
    - "Early Negro Writings", Undated (Box 157, Folder 1355)
    - Ethel Mercedes Sutton, family paper, Undated (Box 158, Folder 1356)
    - Fisk University Speech, 1968- (Box 158, Folder 1357)
    - Harriet Tubman, Circa 1963 (Box 158, Folder 1358)
    - Howard University, Alumni Award remarks, Undated (Box 158, Folder 1359)
    - Howard University, Charter Day Class of 1928, remarks, Undated (Box 158, Folder 1360)
    - Howard University Faculty Wives Club remarks, 1958-1963 (Box 158, Folder 1361)
    - James A. Porter Colloquium, Introductory remarks, 1993- (Box 158, Folder 1362)
    - "The Librarian and the Scholar: A Working Partnership", 1965- (Box 158, Folder 1363)
    - "Library, Archives, Museums and Other Cultural Centers", Undated (Box 158, Folder 1364)
    - "Literary Accomplishments of Negro Women", 1951- (Box 158, Folder 1365)
    - Louisville Library Club, Undated (Box 158, Folder 1366)
    - Martin Luther King Library, 1992- (Box 158, Folder 1367)
    - Michael Winston, 1973- (Box 158, Folder 1368)
    - Moorland Spingarn Research Center, Circa 1967 (Box 158, Folder 1369)
    - National Library Week, Undated (Box 158, Folder 1370)
    - Negro authors, Undated (Box 158, Folder 1371)
    - "Negro Women in Our Wars: Unsung Heros", Circa 1940 (Box 158, Folder 1372)
    - "Negro Women and Their Achievements", 1955- (Box 158, Folder 1373)
    - Nineteenth Century African American Females in Great Britain, 1991- (Box 158, Folder 1374)
    - "Of Men and Records", 1957- (Box 158, Folder 1375)
    - "The People Portrayed", Undated (Box 158, Folder 1376)
    - Portuguese Colonial Historiography, Undated (Box 159, Folder 1377)
    - "A Proposal for the Establishment of a Committee on Howard University Archives", 1942- (Box 159, Folder 1378)
    - "Remembering the Legacy, Renewing the Spirit and Challenging in the Nineties and Beyond", Undated (Box 159, Folder 1379)
    - "Repositories of Materials on Negro Life and History: An Endless Quest", Undated (Box 159, Folder 1380)
    - Retirement Ceremony of Lois Gertrude Dozier, Remarks, Undated (Box 159, Folder 1381)
    - "Research Centers and Sources for the Study of African History", Undated (Box 159, Folder 1382)
    - "The Role of the Negro Collection in Teaching and Research at Howard University", 1967- (Box 159, Folder 1383)
    - "Sarah Parker Remond", Undated (Box 159, Folder 1384)
    - "Self-Cultivation Through Reading", Circa 1964 (Box 159, Folder 1385)
    - Self-Culture Club, Lecture, 1943- (Box 159, Folder 1386)
    - Shiloh Missionary Baptist Church, 1987- (Box 159, Folder 1387)
    - Symposium on Candidates for Rediscovery: The Boston Version, 1975- (Box 159, Folder 1388)
    - A Tribute to Mrs. Ruby Myse Kendrick, 1986- (Box 159, Folder 1389)
    - Yale University Libraries, Undated (Box 159, Folder 1390)
    - Untitled Speeches, Circa 1948-1995 (Box 159, Folder 1391-1396)
    - Untitled Speeches, Circa 1948-1995 (Box 160, Folder 1397)
    - Notes, Circa 1948-1995 (Box 160, Folder 1398-1400)
  - Writings, 1928-1995
    This subseries is organized into six groupings: Writings by Dorothy Porter Wesley; Writings about or in Dedication of Dorothy Porter Wesley; Writings by James A. Porter; Writings by Charles H. Wesley; Writings by Constance Porter Uzelac; and Writings by Others.
    - Writings by Dorothy Porter Wesley
      - "African and Caribbean Creative Writings: A Bibliographic Survey", 1966- (Box 161, Folder 1401)
      - "The African Collection at Howard University", 1959- (Box 161, Folder 1402)
      - African History (Egypt and Ethiopia), 1933- (Box 161, Folder 1403)
      - African Writers (draft), Undated (Box 161, Folder 1404)
      - Afro-American Writings Published Before 1835, Outline, 1931- (Box 161, Folder 1405)
      - Annotated Bibliography on American Negro Seperatism, Undated (Box 161, Folder 1406)
      - Annual Report to the President of Howard University 1960-1961 (Box 161, Folder 1407)
      - Anti-Slavery Movement in Northampton, 1954-1960 (Box 161, Folder 1408)
      - Autobiography of a Fugitive Negro by Samuel Ringgold Ward; Introduction by Dorothy Porter Wesley, 1968- (Box 161, Folder 1409)
      - Behind the Scenes Thirty Years a Slave and Four Years in the White House By Elizabeth Keckley, Introduction by Dorothy Porter Wesley, 1968- (Box 161, Folder 1410)
      - "Bibliography and Research in African American Scholarship", 1976- (Box 161, Folder 1411-1412)
      - "A Bibliographical checklist of American Negro Writers About Africa", 1958- (Box 161, Folder 1413)
      - Black Biliographers and Collectors Sources and Notes (draft), 1989-1990 (Box 162, Folder 1414)
      - "The Black Role During the Era of the Revolution", 1973- (Box 162, Folder 1415-1416)
      - Black Women in America: An Historical Encyclopedia (Contributer), 1992- (Box 162, Folder 1417)
      - The Black Women in American Society: An Annotated Bibliography by Lenwood. G. Davis foreword by Dorothy Porter Wesley, 1975-1978 (Box 162, Folder 1418-1419)